Guide to the Robert O. Tilman Papers
Robert O. Tilman Papers
1950s-1980s
1950 1987
Tilman Robert O.
MC 00092
The papers of Robert O. Tilman document his career as assistant and associate professor at Yale University, professor of political science and dean of the College of Humanities and Social Sciences at North Carolina State University, and other professional activities related to Southeast Asian studies. A small part of the collection, mostly slides and photographs, deals with Tilman’s personal life. The collection includes correspondence; course material, such as syllabi and lecture notes; administrative files; files relating to various professional activities; manuscripts; publications; material from a research project about Filipino identity; reference files; personal files including those related to his wife Jo Tilman; audiovisual material such as video cassettes, tape reels, slides and photographs; artifacts; and computer-related material.
Robert O. Tilman (1929-1987) was professor of political science, 1971-1987; dean of the College of Humanities and Social Sciences, 1971-1984; and founder of the North Carolina Japan Center at North Carolina State University. Tilman was an expert in Southeast Asian political systems.
25.25 linear feet
28 archival boxes, 3 archival half boxes, 7 cartons
North Carolina State University Libraries, Special Collections Research Center
This collection is arranged into the following series: Correspondence, Course Material, Administrative Files, Professional Activities, Manuscripts and Writings, Research Project, Reference Files, Personal Files, Audio-Visual Material, Artifacts, and Computer Material.
Robert O. Tilman (1929-1987) was professor of political science, 1971-1987; dean of the College of Humanities and Social Sciences, 1971-1984; and founder of the North Carolina Japan Center at North Carolina State University. Tilman was an expert in Southeast Asian political systems.
Tilman was a member of the Association for Asian Studies, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, Asia Society, Southeastern Regional Conference on Asian Studies, XXVII International Congress of Orientalists, American Political Science Association, Southern Political Science Association, American Conference of Academic Deans, and the Board of Directors of the Triange University Center for Advanced Studies. His honors included membership in Phi Beta Kappa and Phi Kappa Phi, as well as selection as an American Society of International Law Fellow, 1963; American Council of Learned Societies Fellow, 1964; National Science Foundation Senior Fellow, 1969-1970; American Philosophical Society Fellow, 1974; and Fulbright Senior Research Fellow, 1982-1983.
Tilman received a B.S. from Memphis State University in 1957; M.A. from Duke University in 1959; and Ph.D. from Duke University in 1961. He was employed by the United State Army Security Agency from 1951 to 1954 and the National Security Agency from 1954 to 1957 before he began his teaching career. He was an assistant professor at Tulane University, 1962-1965; assistant and associate professor at Yale University, 1965-1970; senior research fellow at Columbia University, 1970-1971; and professor at North Carolina State University, 1971-1987.
Born in Caruthersville, Missouri, on 21 July 1929, Tilman married Jo Carolyn Huddleston on 19 December 1954. Tilman died on 23 August 1987.
The papers of Robert O. Tilman document his career as assistant and associate professor at Yale University, professor of political science and dean of the College of Humanities and Social Sciences at North Carolina State University, and other professional activities related to Southeast Asian studies. A small part of the collection, mostly slides and photographs, deals with Tilman’s personal life. The collection includes correspondence; course material, such as syllabi and lecture notes; administrative files; files relating to various professional activities; manuscripts; publications; material from a research project about Filipino identity; reference files; personal files including those related to his wife Jo Tilman; audiovisual material such as video cassettes, tape reels, slides and photographs; artifacts; and computer-related material.
ASEAN; Yale University; Lee Kuan Yew 1923-; Association for Asian Studies Committee on Research Materials on Southeast Asia; Laurel Salvador H. (Salvador Hidalgo) 1928-2004; North Carolina State University--Faculty--History--20th century; Tilman Robert O.; North Carolina State University Department of Political Science and Public Administration; Tilman Robert O.; North Carolina State University College of Humanities and Social Sciences; Raleigh (N.C.); North Carolina Study and teaching Political science; Universities and colleges Administration; Indonesia; Journals (periodicals); Malaysia; Periodicals; Singapore; Philippines; Asian languages; United States Southeast Asia Study and teaching; Maps; North Carolina History 20th century College teachers; Photographs; 20th century Asia Politics and government; Political socialization Philippines; Asia Political leadership; Washington (D.C.)
- Correspondence
  This series contains correspondence arranged chronologically from 1963 to 1987. Several files are arranged topically rather than chronologically, reflecting original order. The letters deal with various aspects of Tilman’s career, including job proposals, publishing, research, meetings and conferences, and correspondence with colleagues.
  - Correspondence, 1963-1964; 1963 1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1966; 1965 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1969; 1967 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1971; 1970 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1975; 1972 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1978; 1976 1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1979; 1979 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1986; 1981 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1987; 1987 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Book Project Correspondence, 1963-1968; 1963 1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Research Analysis Corporation Correspondence, 1964-1967; 1964 1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript Reprint Correspondence, 1967-1968; 1967 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous and Undated Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Course Materials
  This series includes syllabi, lecture notes, exams and quizzes, and reading material for political science classes taught at Yale University and North Carolina State University.
  - Yale University
    - Lecture Material Political Science 63/180 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Lecture Material (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Lectures (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Lecture Materials (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Diversity (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Economic and Foreign Trade (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Legal and Constitutional (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Man, State, and Society (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Man, State, and Society in Contemporary Southeast Asia (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Politics - Sarawak and Sabah (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Politics - Singapore and Malaysia (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Sarawak - General and Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - North Carolina State University
    - PS 201 American Government (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - PS 201-011 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - PS 231-001 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - PS 231-002 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - PS 231 - International Relations (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - PS 231 - Required Readings (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - PS 231 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - HSS 300 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - HSS 300 Islam (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Islam and Politics Course (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - PS 303 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 343 Material (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - PS 343 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - PS 343, Fall 84 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Course Action Forms (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Student Papers (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Student Papers (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Thesis - Mark Swaringen, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Photographs (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Administrative Files
  This series includes information about a cooperative program between North Carolina State University and the University of the Philippines, a scholarly communications computer program developed at North Carolina State University, and other miscellaneous materials. This series also contains files arranged alphabetically as Tilman had them.
  - Hong Liu (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - North Carolina State University Benefits (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - North Carolina State University - Univeristy of the Philippines Program (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Polinet (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - ScholarNet (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Vita and Bibliography (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Yale, 1970; 1970 1970 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Alphabetical Files - A (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Alphabetical Files - B (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Alphabetical Files - D (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Alphabetical Files - E (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Alphabetical Files - F (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Alphabetical Files - G (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Alphabetical Files - H (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Alphabetical Files - I (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Alphabetical Files - ISEAS (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Alphabetical Files - J (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Alphabetical Files - K (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Alphabetical Files - M (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Alphabetical Files - N (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Alphabetical Files - O (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Alphabetical Files - P (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Alphabetical Files - R (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Alphabetical Files - S (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Alphabetical Files - T (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Alphabetical Files - U (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Alphabetical Files - V (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Alphabetical Files - W (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Alphabetical Files - Unfiled (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Professional Activities
  This series contains material related to Tilman’s involvement with various professional committees, organizations, conferences, and associations. A substantial portion deals with the Association of Southeast Asian Nations. Also included are book and article reviews written by Tilman, a survey of Southeast Asian specialists, and information relating to Singaporean Prime Minister Kuan Yew Lee’s visit to Washington, D.C. and Raleigh, N.C. in 1985.
  - Association of Southeast Asian Nations
    - Abstracts (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Abstracts (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Conference Papers (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Draft of Proposal (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Funding and Expenses (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Hiroshima Lecture, 1980; 1980 1980 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Meeting Report (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Notes (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Research Proposal (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - The States of ASEAN (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Conferences and Committees
    - AAS Program Review (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Asia Society Vouchers (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Conferences (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Conferences (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Conferences (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - CORMOSEA (Committee on Research Materials on Southeast Asia) (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - International Security in Southeast Asia (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Interuniversity Southeast Asia Committee (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Malaysia-Singapore Research Group (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - SEADAG (Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group) (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - SERC Annual Report, 1972-1973; 1972 1973 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Southeast Asia: Post Vietnam, 1973; 1973 1973 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Tawain Symposium, 1973; 1973 1973 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Southeast Asian Specialists Survey
    - Biographical Survey Project (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Coding Key (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Surveys (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Surveys (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Book and Article Reviews
    - Reviews (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Reviews (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Reviews (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Reviews (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Reviews (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Reviews (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Notes from interview with Mah Shu Li (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Invitations and Clippings from Washington, D.C. Events (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Prime Minister Lee (Singapore) Visit to Raleigh, 1985; 1985 1985 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Manuscripts and Writings
  This series contains manuscripts, essays, and other writings by Tilman. Several drafts of an Association of Southeast Asian Nations manuscript titled Southeast Asia and the Enemy Beyond Its Shores and essays for a book project edited by Tilman titled Six Perspectives on Southeast Asia are included. This series also contains miscellaneous notes and note cards, some of which relate to the manuscripts.
  - The Chinese of the Philippines: Between Scylla and Charybdis (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Chinese-language Education and the Future of the Philippine-Chinese (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Confucius among the Barbarians: Philippine-Chinese Youth and the Struggle to Perpetuate a Chinese Subculture (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Elections in Sarawak (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Guide to British Library Holdings of Publications Relating to Malaysia in the Field of the Social Sciences (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - In Quest of Unity: Search for a Malaysian Nation (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - The Intermediary in Philippine Politics: An Exploratory Study (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Intra-elite Relations: Kinship, The Middleman, and Political Continuity in the Philippines (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Malaysia: The Problems of Federation (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Malaysia: The Social Context of the Federal Experiment (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Malaysian Federalism: Law and Politics in a Plural Society (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - The Philippine-Indonesian Threat and the Growth of a Malaysian Nation (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - The Philippines in 1970 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Policy Formulation, Policy Execution, and the Political Elite Structure of Contemporary Malaya (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Political Leadership in Singapore (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Political Organization of the Malacca Sultanate (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - The Process of Political Integration (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - A Proposal to Create an Intra-ASEAN and ASEAN-American Computer Network for the Exchange of Scholarly Information (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Public Service Commissions in the Federation of Malaya (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - The Role of the Colonial Services in the Administrative and Economic Development of Malaya (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Singapore Foreign Policy under the PAP (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Variations on a Theme: The Alliance Pattern in Malaysian Politics (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Whither Sabah and Sarawak? (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Six Perspectives on Southeast Asia
    - Six Perspectives on Southeast Asia (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Six Perspectives on Southeast Asia (continued) (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Southeast Asia - Gosling, early copy (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Southeast Asia - Gosling, final (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Southeast Asia - Paauw, early copy (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Southeast Asia - Schegel, early copy (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Southeast Asia - Schegel, final (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Southeast Asia - Steinberg, early (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Southeast Asia - Steinberg, final (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Southeast Asia - Swearer, early copy (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Southeast Asia - Swearer, final (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Southeast Asia - Tilman, early copy (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Southeast Asia and the Enemy Beyond Its Shores
    - Southeast Asian and the Enemy Beyond, published form (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - I. Tiger at the Door: Threats and Perceptions (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - II. Southeast Asia and ASEAN: The Setting and the Context (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - III. Policy Formulation: The Policy Makers and The Policy Setting (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - IV. The USSR and Vietnam: Perceptions of the Partners and the Partnership (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - V. China: Ally or Adversary (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - VI. Japan: Ambivalence Toward a Partnership (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - VII. The United States: The Risks of Friendship (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - VIII. Tigers at the Door and Tigers in the Kitchen: External and Internal Threats in Perspective (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Bibliography (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Tiger at the Door, draft (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - The USSR and Vietnam, draft (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Tiger at the Door, edited version (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Notes (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Material to Check (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Citations to Add (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Information from Publisher (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Notes and Note Cards
    - Miscellaneous notes and notecards (Carton 33)
- Research Project
  This series contains materials from a research project conducted by Tilman in the Philippines in the late 1960s. The study addressed Chinese identity in Filipino youth. Included in this series are background reference materials relating to socialization and political identity; preliminary and final reports; instructions for scoring the questionnaires; and thirty-five respondent files from Filipino students.
  - Back-up Code Book (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Bibliography (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Chinese Textbook Translations (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Coding Information (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - De Guzman Paper (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Depth Interview Guide (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Depth Pictures 1 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Depth Pictures 2 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Depth Pictures 3 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Depth Pictures 4 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Depth Pictures 5 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Depth Pictures 6 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Depth Pictures 7 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Depth Pictures 8 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Duplicate Lecture Notes (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Duplicate Newspaper Extracts (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Duplicate Talks (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Elections Article (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - EMM Scale (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Evangelista Interview (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Extracts from Newspapers (Chinese) (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Extracts from Newspapers (English) (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - The Family (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Final Field Report (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Independent Variables (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Index of Chineseness (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Index to Chamber Clipings on Ch. Ed. (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Interview Schedules, Appointments, etc. (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Liu Chi Tien, History of Chinese Schools (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Manuscript and Bibliography (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Mid-year Progress Report (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Duplicates (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Material (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Working Papers (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Notes etc. re. Thurstone Sealing (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - NS7 - Working File (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Outline Ideas (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Philippine Constitution (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Philippine Hua-Ch'iao: General and Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Philippine Population (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Political Alienation (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Press Statements (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Pretest Material (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Programming Material (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Project Correspondence and Miscellaneous (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Reading Material (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Research Material (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - "Scylla and Charybdis" Paper (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Socialization, etc. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Student Activism and Organizations (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - "Student Unrest" Paper (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - YCC Work in Progress (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Respondent Files
    - Respondent 1 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Respondent 2 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Respondent 3 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Respondent 4 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Respondent 5 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Respondent 6 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Respondent 7 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Respondent 8 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Respondent 9 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Respondent 10 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Respondent 11 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Respondent 12 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Respondent 13 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Respondent 14 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Respondent 15 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Respondent 16 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Respondent 17 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Respondent 18 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Respondent 19 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Respondent 20 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Respondent 21 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Respondent 22 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Respondent 23 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Respondent 24 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Respondent 25 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Respondent 26 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Respondent 27 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Respondent 28 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Respondent 29 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Respondent 30 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Respondent 31 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Respondent 32 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Respondent 33 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Respondent 34 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Respondent 35 (Box 24, Folder 14)
- Reference Files
  This series contains miscellaneous material including article reprints, photocopied book excerpts, maps, and abstracts, and publications relating to Southeast Asia. Publications include reports, bulletins, newsletters, journals, and news clippings. Also included are foreign language materials and speeches by various Asian leaders.
  - Abstract IX Southeast Asia (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Asian Survey 1970 Wrap-up (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - The Confidential Coup (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Curricula vitae (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Dissertation (unidentified title and author) (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Indonesia (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Laurel, Salvador H. (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Leadership Paper (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Malaysia (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Philippines (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - The Role of the Military in Indonesia (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Singapore (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Sulu Claim - Philippine Case (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Thailand (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Maps (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Foreign Language Material
    - Bahasa Indonesia (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - English Index to Matthews Chinese-English Dictionary (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Atlas (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Speeches by Foreign Leaders
    - Lee Kuan Yew: Speeches, Statements, Press Reports, 1966-1967; 1966 1967 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Lee Kuan Yew: Speeches, Statements, Press Reports, 1968-1970; 1968 1970 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - S. Rajaratnam: Speeches, Statements, etc., 1965-1970; 1965 1970 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Singapore U.N. G.A. Statements, 1965-1970; 1965 1970 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Singapore: Miscellaneous, 1965-1971 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Publications
    - Report on the British Military Administration of Malaya, 1945-1946; 1945 1946 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Report of the Public Services Salaries Commission of Malaya, 1947; 1947 1947 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Report on Revision of Salaries in the Public Services of the Federation of Malaya and the Colony of Singapore, 1949; 1949 1949 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Report on the Emergency in Malaya, 1950-1951; 1950 1951 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Publications, 1962; 1962 1962 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Publications, 1975; 1975 1975 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Publications, 1984-1985; 1984 1985 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Publications, 1986; 1986 1986 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Publications, 1987; 1987 1987 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Publications, 1987; 1987 1987 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Publications, 1987; 1987 1987 (Box 20, Folder 4)